<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.3.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-11-10T14:30:28+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks//</id><title type="html">Neubloc - www.neubloc.pl</title><subtitle>An amazing website.</subtitle><author><name>Your Name</name></author><entry><title type="html">Why RightSource to South America?</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-27-37-why-rightsource-to-south-america/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why RightSource to South America?" /><published>2014-02-27T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/37-why-rightsource-to-south-america</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-27-37-why-rightsource-to-south-america/">&lt;p&gt;South America might not seem like a possibility when outsourcing software development, but with Argentina and Ecuador emerging as the next IT hotspots, Neubloc encourages companies to rethink their outsourcing destination. Neubloc also offers its development and “follow the sun” models to help companies RightSource the “right” way.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;h1&gt;Why Argentina?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Argentina is not only eagerly adopting IT, it has become a regional leader in the research and development of advanced technologies. With many industries to choose from, Argentina is ideal ground for start-ups and it offers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; A large pool of talented technical professionals:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/WhySouthAmerica1.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Over 100 institutions supporting IT&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; A stable, growing economic platform&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Why Ecuador?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ecuador has excellent university training in technical skills and its institutions offer higher-level degrees in mathematics, engineering, and computer science. Moreover, Ecuador’s growing software industry promises:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; A diverse, low cost labor pool&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; High English fluency&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; A strong resource pool for web technologies&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; An expanding IT sector:&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/WhySouthAmerica2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both countries enforce IP laws similar to the US and Europe, unlike their Indian and Chinese counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;RightSourcing the Right Way&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neubloc has extensive experience working with startups from seed stage all the way to their I.P.O. and has overseen all stages of the product development process. By following specific models, Neubloc has RightSourced software design and development throughout the United States, Eastern Europe and South America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help make the transition, Neubloc makes rightsourcing to South America easier with their development model by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Maximizing utilization of resources&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Making effectively use of time&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Allowing around-the-clock software development&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Reducing labor and overhead costs&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Implementing through near or offshore development centers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neubloc also uses the “follow the sun” model, which utilizes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; A whole project management team instead of a single overall project manager&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Additional time for setup and code management&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Enough time to build and explain detailed specifications as well as requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So whether a company is well-developed or just starting out, South America offers a wide variety of skilled labor, reduced IP risk and economically stable grounds for RightSourcing software design and development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
  For more information on this topic, read our full discussion &lt;a href=&quot;../case-studies/white-papers/why-rightsource-to-south-america.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">South America might not seem like a possibility when outsourcing software development, but with Argentina and Ecuador emerging as the next IT hotspots, Neubloc encourages companies to rethink their outsourcing destination. Neubloc also offers its development and “follow the sun” models to help companies RightSource the “right” way.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jest w Polsce nowym Hotspot IT?</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-20-36-poland-the-new-it-hotspot/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jest w Polsce nowym Hotspot IT?" /><published>2014-02-20T01:29:33+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-20T01:29:33+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/36-poland-the-new-it-hotspot</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-20-36-poland-the-new-it-hotspot/">&lt;p&gt;India has long dominated other countries as the top destination for outsourcing Information Technology (IT), but with the rise in attrition rates and other fall outs, is there a better alternative? Some companies seem to think so and they are looking to Poland.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;!--more--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three main advantages to choosing Poland for outsourcing IT projects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. A more favorable time zone: there is a mere 6 hour difference between Poland and New York, compared to around 11 hours difference between New Delhi and New York.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Similar work ethics: the Poles are problem solvers and independent thinkers. They tend to follow the US work style where if a problem crops up, the team will try to solve it instead of stalling as they await orders from management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Enforced legal regulations: India is notorious for IP theft and carries a high risk, but Poland has similar IP protection laws to the US, that are actually enforced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these attractive benefits, Poland has lured many companies to invest in its service hubs. The cities of Wroclaw and Gdansk house software giants from India like Infosys, Wipro and Tata Consulting Services. IBM is also utilizing what Poland has to offer along, with large banks like Citigroup and Bank of New York Mellon. With Poland’s business sector booming, there is a high chance that it will surpass the automobile industry, which has long been the leading source for private sector jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is unfortunately one drawback to outsourcing in Poland: a higher cost. During the global economic crisis, Poland was one of the few countries to remain stable. Salaries in Poland are higher than salaries in countries like India for entering developers and the cost of renting space is larger as well - but there is always a solution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondary and tertiary cities, away from the major cities, offer lower rents and are generally less expensive to live in, which allows companies to tweak the salary range. Lodz, Proznan, Wroclaw, and Krakow are just a few choices that can help reduce costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when cost is an issue, it becomes important to consider these advantages that Poland offers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. A greater flexibility in terms of the number of cities and the level of skilled workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. A decreased time to bring products to market because of the independent Polish work ethic and the high education of many Poles which makes them apt problem solvers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. A chance to enter the attractive Eastern European market with solutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skilled software developers are hard to find in most European countries and many developers who work in the United States or Western Europe tend to prefer managerial positions or venture into careers as consultants as they gain experience. This creates a shortage of developers, but Poland has many developers with these qualifications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland is the best choice to outsource to for smaller projects that require a lot of innovation and it has a great talent pool for smaller, less seasoned companies to choose from to speed up the development process, saving both time and money. Hence, for both large and small companies, nearshoring development projects to Poland is a great choice when considering both costs and quality talent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Works Cited&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. Horsten, Peter. &quot;The surprising Polish IT Outsourcing potential.&quot; PetersOpinion.com. N.p., 8 4 2013. Web. 15 Jan 2014. &lt;http://petersopinion.com/2013/04/08/the-surprising-polish-it-outsourcing-potential/&gt;&lt;/http:&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Ewing, Jack. &quot;Midsize Cities in Poland Develop as Service Hubs for Outsourcing Industry.&quot; Business. The New York Times, 22 12 2013. Web. 15 Jan 2014. &lt;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/12/23/business/international/midsize-cities-in-poland-develop-as-service-hubs-for-outsourcing-industry.html&gt;&lt;/http:&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. &quot;The World Clock.&quot; . timeanddate.com, n.d. Web. 15 Jan 2014. &lt;http://www.timeanddate.com/worldclock/difference.html?p1=176&gt;&lt;/http:&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">India has long dominated other countries as the top destination for outsourcing Information Technology (IT), but with the rise in attrition rates and other fall outs, is there a better alternative? Some companies seem to think so and they are looking to Poland.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/Is_poland_new_spot.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Costs of Outsourcing to Poland</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-20-34-costs-of-outsourcing-to-poland/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Costs of Outsourcing to Poland" /><published>2014-02-20T01:29:33+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-20T01:29:33+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/34-costs-of-outsourcing-to-poland</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-20-34-costs-of-outsourcing-to-poland/">&lt;p&gt;Only a decade or so ago, well-educated Poles and fresh graduates had to venture outside Poland to find jobs in the IT and software development sectors. Now, outsourcing for IT and software development is Poland’s largest employment sector. Even software giants outside the US and Western Europe, like Infosys from India, are shifting projects to Poland.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;../images/costofOStoPol1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;!--more--&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Poland easily attracts interest because of the low costs associated with operating there. Labor costs in Poland are 50% less than Western Europe. Regional cities like Poznan, Wroclaw, and Krakow have considerably lower rents (about 10 Euro less per square meter) than major cities like Warsaw (Cienski).&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s no surprise than that service centers are drifting from large secondary cities to more tertiary ones, very unlike other outsourcing countries where offshore centers tend to cluster around capital cities. Fueling thisdrift are large regional business centers outside of Warsaw. These businesses have lower costs because they reside outside the central districts and outsourcing companies can utilize these to save expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Although Poland has higher labor costs than India, the costs are significantly less compared to hiring in the US or Germany, which proves a major advantage to companies in the US and Western Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt; &lt;img src=&quot;../images/costofOStoPol2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The chart above categorizes salaries in Poland as a fraction of US salaries for the same positions catalogued in 2010. While some top-tier positions like Operations Manager earn about the same salary as that in the US, the salaries for Senior Software Engineers or IT Project Managers are less than 50% of the cost that it would be in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In summary, the costs of outsourcing to Poland are significantly less when considering the highly skilled labor available in this country with a stable economy and expanding business sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Works Cited&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. Cienski, Jan. &quot;Outsourcing: Businesses go east to offshore costly services.&quot; Global Property Insights. The Financial Times LTD, 23 08 2013. Web. 4 Jan 2014.
        &lt;http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/66e94cbe-8667-11e2-ad73-00144feabdc0.html&gt;&lt;/http:&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. &quot;Poland.&quot; . SourcingLine, n.d. Web. 4 Jan 2014.
        &lt;https://www.sourcingline.com/outsourcing-location/poland&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">Only a decade or so ago, well-educated Poles and fresh graduates had to venture outside Poland to find jobs in the IT and software development sectors. Now, outsourcing for IT and software development is Poland’s largest employment sector. Even software giants outside the US and Western Europe, like Infosys from India, are shifting projects to Poland.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How and Where to Outsource your Development</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-20-35-how-and-where-to-outsource-your-development/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How and Where to Outsource your Development" /><published>2014-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/35-how-and-where-to-outsource-your-development</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-20-35-how-and-where-to-outsource-your-development/">&lt;p&gt;For a startup, outsourcing product development is not easy. In contrast, large companies routinely establish outsource development operations because they have greater time, scale, resources and brand recognition to attract and maintain engineering talent. Even without size or leverage, outsourced product development is the only realistic option for early stage technology companies. So how do you ensure proper partner selection and good management to outsource successfully? Read on!&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h1 style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. What Should I Outsource?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;Over the past few years, outsourcing has evolved to embrace outsourcing products early in their development cycle and outsourcing products that are highly innovative. Neubloc recently sourced Proximetry’s management and development teams in Poland to work on their innovative wireless industry product. After establishing the right communication structure to keep the development and management teams in touch on the changes, Proximetry delivered their product to market on time for a third of the cost and experienced zero attrition in the first three years of development!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;The key to this success is the hybrid development approach: an onshore presence to the outsource supplier. The purpose of the onshore presence is to work on a design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;Neubloc also designates a team lead onsite for 4 – 8 weeks to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;1. Learn requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;2. Design&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;3. Find client team stakeholders&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;If the team is large and cost is not an issue, the lead can stay indefinitely onsite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. How do I Select a Vendor?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;Selecting a vendor is based on choosing between two client engagement models employed by software development firms: staff augmentation and project management. If the product is fully specified, either model works, but most startups are better off using the project management model because the project output is the core product. Staff augment provides labor at the lowest to ‘augment’ an existing engineering team. Project and team management is provided by the product company rather than the outsource firm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;Cons to using staff augmentation include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;1. Difficulty communicating culturally and logistically&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;2. Changing specifications that cause discontinuous communication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;3. Difficulties measuring achievements/productivity of offshore team members&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;The project management model uses the technical team lead offshore as the single point of contact. This model enables measureable team productivity and project achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;It is also critical to understand the outsource firm’s principal focus. Grow the development team overtime instead of using offshore startups or organizations too small to meet the requirements of fifty or more engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Where Should I Base my Development?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;Although most US companies outsource firms to India, they experience backlash from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;1. Decreased productivity due to high attrition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;2. Higher risk of IP threat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;3. Lower quality work due to communication/cultural pitfalls&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;Alternatively, Eastern Europe is more attractive for software development, especially countries within the European Union. Pros to choosing Eastern Europe include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;1. A high level of education&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;2. An innovative spirit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;3. Low attrition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 90px;&quot;&gt;4. Low associated cost&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;Regardless of company size, with proper partner selection and management, outsourcing is often the best way a founding team, along with their investors, can realize a positive exit for their company.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">For a startup, outsourcing product development is not easy. In contrast, large companies routinely establish outsource development operations because they have greater time, scale, resources and brand recognition to attract and maintain engineering talent. Even without size or leverage, outsourced product development is the only realistic option for early stage technology companies. So how do you ensure proper partner selection and good management to outsource successfully? Read on!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Costs of Outsourcing to China and India</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-20-33-costs-of-outsourcing-china-and-india/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Costs of Outsourcing to China and India" /><published>2014-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/33-costs-of-outsourcing-china-and-india</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-20-33-costs-of-outsourcing-china-and-india/">&lt;p&gt;For companies in the United States and Western Europe looking to outsource, India and China are no longer the only choices. Outsourcing has bolstered India’s booming IT industry and China’s unparalleled manufacturing sector throughout the years, raising the standard of living. These changes have had long term effects and have significantly changed the costs of outsourcing to these countries.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Back in 2005, the cost of manufacturing in China was 25% to 30% of the US cost, but improvements in China's economy and the stability of its currency have driven manufacturing costs up. According to the Huffington Post, manufacturing costs in China will equal US costs by 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The standard of living in China is also on a rapid rise, with wages increasing an average of 12% annually. Companies in China have to keep wages high if they want to attract and retain skilled workers, which has increased the competition and cost of labor.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While some companies are pulling out of China to outsource elsewhere, others are moving away from big cities like Shanghai and settling in other less expensive cities. India used to be a better alternative to China for IT outsourcing, but it is now experiencing issues similar to those occurring in China.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Salaries in India have risen 10% to 15% just in the last year. Many companies are looking in alternative countries for inexpensive and qualified developers. While inexpensive labor can be found in the graduates churned out by the thousands every year from numerous universities, finding skilled labor is much more expensive. Compared to other countries, employees higher up the ladder earn vastly more than their less skilled counterparts, as can be seen in the figure below.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/costofOStoChInd.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Companies that are pulling out from China and India are setting their sights on Eastern Europe, in countries like Poland, or South America, in countries like Argentina. These countries offer the same or better IT and software development services, with skilled labor, for lower wages. The overall cost of setting up an outsourcing firm is also comparatively less in these countries and they have better IP protection.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;
  Works Cited
&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. LeBeau, Phillip. &quot;U.S. Manufacturing No More Expensive Than Outsourcing To China By 2015: Study.&quot;Huffington Post 09 01 2014, n. pag. Web. 9 Jan. 2014.
        &lt;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/04/19/china-manufacturing-costs_n_3116638.html&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. &quot;Rising Costs Threaten India's Hold on Offshore IT.&quot;Outsourcing to India. N.p., n.d. Web. 10 Jan 2014.
        &lt;http://www.outsourcing-india.biz/rising-costs-threaten-india-s-hold-on-offshore-it&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">For companies in the United States and Western Europe looking to outsource, India and China are no longer the only choices. Outsourcing has bolstered India’s booming IT industry and China’s unparalleled manufacturing sector throughout the years, raising the standard of living. These changes have had long term effects and have significantly changed the costs of outsourcing to these countries.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Conducting Co-Design Sessions</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-17-32-conducting-co-design-sessions/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conducting Co-Design Sessions" /><published>2014-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/32-conducting-co-design-sessions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-17-32-conducting-co-design-sessions/">&lt;p&gt;Because the co-design approach is iterative, it is necessary for all design engineers, developers, and target users to assemble for mapping future steps. Conducting these sessions is all about careful planning. First, confirm all attendees and ensure they are notified of the dates and times.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Participating attendees should include:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. Two facilitators, one of whom is a note-taker&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. At least two target users (7-8 maximum)&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. One or more development engineers to gain insight and user context&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure the participants gather in a comfortable place during the workshop, with adequate table space and whiteboards. Use flip-charts and post-it notes to capture details and concepts. Digital cameras can be used to capture notes and concepts sketched on the whiteboard.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The first step to a successful co-design session begins with defining goals:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. Start with an introduction that gives a quick review&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Clearly communicate objectives and expectations&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Identify what each participant expects as an outcome of the workshop&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;4. Reference using existing diagrams&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;5. Discuss existing system and domain issues&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;6. Validate the workflow&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;7. Identify and document the usability goals the design must meet&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once all participants are familiar with the goals, begin the co-design exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. To start things, use some unfinished concepts or compelling products as good/bad examples&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Prompt users for suggestions and encourage them to illustrate the concept&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Tape concepts and screens to the wall for maximum visibility and retention&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Co-design is an iterative process and it is important to keep revisiting things learned in the co-design to optimize user input. It is also important to use this knowledge to refine initial designs. After developing a high level product prototype, conduct a usability study to test the refined design. Usability tasks are used to measure the:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. Effectiveness&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Efficiency&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Satisfaction&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;of the design without leading or influencing users. Information and feedback from target users can be used again to refine the design before expensive development begins. Depending on the size and complexity of the design effort, these steps are often iterative to cover different features and/or design enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
For more information on co-design, see our full discussion &lt;a href=&quot;../case-studies/white-papers/utilizing-co-design-to-create-market-driven-products.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">Because the co-design approach is iterative, it is necessary for all design engineers, developers, and target users to assemble for mapping future steps. Conducting these sessions is all about careful planning. First, confirm all attendees and ensure they are notified of the dates and times.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pros and Cons of Outsourcing Software Design and Development</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-17-31-pros-and-cons-of-outsourcing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pros and Cons of Outsourcing Software Design and Development" /><published>2014-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/31-pros-and-cons-of-outsourcing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-17-31-pros-and-cons-of-outsourcing/">&lt;p&gt;In today’s global and fast-paced economy, outsourcing provides enriching opportunities for companies that save both time and money. However, in order to make the most of these third parties, it is important to understand their advantages as well as their disadvantages.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;h1&gt;Pros&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outsourcing parts of development are beneficial to companies in gaining access to specialized skills such as usability experts, systems architects, and graphic designers. When it comes to software development skills, there are various talent pools spread out globally with technical skills related to geographic specialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third parties from certain areas help cut back labor costs, with no reduction in technical skills, which is helpful for lengthy projects. Moreover, having experts from outsourced teams lends a fresh perspective and helps avoid technical pitfalls that otherwise cost both time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third parties can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. Recruit, since they have in-house staff recruiters ready&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Deploy development infrastructure by supporting the current process with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;1. Managing Projects&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;2. Building Systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;3. Testing Systems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 60px;&quot;&gt;4. Tracking Bugs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Provide Engineering Management, since the management personnel and senior technology personnel are already in place&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;Cons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The greatest setback with outsourcing is when the third party company fails. To prepare for this setback before hand, it is important to put in place preventative measures that give access to the company's developed product and personnel, should it fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More common problems include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. &quot;Double-dipping&quot;, where third parties assign &quot;full time&quot; resources to multiple customers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Intellectual property theft&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Communication barriers across different cultures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;4. Delays and poor implementation due to inefficient management&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to avoid the pitfalls tied to outsourcing is to make the outsourced team integrated into the company, so that its successes and failures become tied to the overall team effort.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">In today’s global and fast-paced economy, outsourcing provides enriching opportunities for companies that save both time and money. However, in order to make the most of these third parties, it is important to understand their advantages as well as their disadvantages.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Product Planning and Co-Design: How to Solve the Problem</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-17-30-co-design-how-to-solve-the-problem/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Product Planning and Co-Design: How to Solve the Problem" /><published>2014-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/30-co-design-how-to-solve-the-problem</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-17-30-co-design-how-to-solve-the-problem/">&lt;p&gt;Good product design effectively and efficiently meets the user’s function and because of this, defining the user is a crucial step that must be completed before beginning design. To accomplish this, user profiles are created that target market segmentation and address the user’s:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. Needs&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Expectations&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Demographics&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;4. Current problems&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;5. Access to available technology and information&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These points make up the contextual knowledge that forms the foundation for co-design. To reach an efficient solution using co-design, it is crucial to keep two things in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. The users are the experts.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Proper planning is absolutely essential.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users are Experts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remember that, though the engineers design the product, it is the user who buys it and therefore the product must be tailored to meet the user’s needs. Make it a priority to identify product champions. Involving users for the long term who are creative will provide fantastic product ideas and lead to a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h1&gt;Proper Planning is Essential&lt;/h1&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Proper planning is essential for successful co-design. To reach a deeper understanding of the problem, review all the research and analysis by:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. Creating user scenarios that represent current user workflows.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Prepare an agenda with a clear purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Highlight the techniques to use.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;4. Stage a do-design session to push the project forward in an organized manner.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h4&gt;
For more information on co-design, see our full discussion &lt;a href=&quot;../case-studies/white-papers/utilizing-co-design-to-create-market-driven-products.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">Good product design effectively and efficiently meets the user’s function and because of this, defining the user is a crucial step that must be completed before beginning design. To accomplish this, user profiles are created that target market segmentation and address the user’s:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Problems with Outsourcing to India</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-17-20-problems-with-outsourcing-to-india/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Problems with Outsourcing to India" /><published>2014-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-02-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/20-problems-with-outsourcing-to-india</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-02-17-20-problems-with-outsourcing-to-india/">&lt;h4&gt;by Armando Viteri, Neubloc, CEO and President&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With major backlash against outsourcing to India, many companies with investments there are now looking for alternatives. Although there is discussion on the wage structure, the issues of outsourcing development services in India are deeper. This paper explores the continual issues with outsourcing development services to India and the shift to other alternatives. &lt;/p&gt;
 

&lt;h2 style=&quot;color: #ad4d27;&quot;&gt;A. High attrition leading to significant drop in productivity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry attrition for Indian software development firms averaged 50% annually, which has only continued to worsen according to the Computer Business Review. Traditionally, large US firms establishing an Indian presence were immune; only recently have companies like Cisco been affected. According to an investment banker, smaller firms currently experience attrition over 100% annually, causing them to look towards development firms in Europe due to their quality of work and low attrition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&quot;color: #ad4d27;&quot;&gt;B. Significant IP Risk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indian firms and court systems are notorious for their lax approach to protecting customers’ source code. Despite the recent steps taken, Indian court systems continue to favor Indian companies no matter the problem. According to Rouse and Co., the global intellectual property consultancy, “Unlike China, there are no administrative remedies available in India for enforcement of intellectual property rights.” Foreign companies face quite the predicament in court cases against an Indian partner who “borrowed” software, and generally do not fare well in these cases. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 style=&quot;color: #ad4d27;&quot;&gt;C. Quality of work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Zinnov, an analyst firm specializing in offshore projects, “more than 75 percent of these cases fall short of expectations.” In addition, experienced employees receive 70% of a US salary after setting up a foreign development shop. Inexpensive talent pools and access to the Indian market are the main reasons for outsourcing, which are not primary objectives for many US software companies. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&quot;color: #ad4d27;&quot;&gt;D. Talent base&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus on embedded development dates back to Poland’s Soviet period. More recently, Poland has been the center of activity in Web 2.0 technologies for both users and developers. By contrast, much of the development work in India focuses on IT instead of software products because it has become difficult to recruit senior and architectural product developers. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 style=&quot;color: #ad4d27;&quot;&gt;F. Work style&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to the US, Poland questions these approaches to test their understanding and challenge assumptions. Time and again it has shown that the Indian work approach requires strict instruction. Indian teams regularly stop for clarification instead of making their own decisions. After accounting for attrition, productivity is surprisingly low.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h2 style=&quot;color: #ad4d27;&quot;&gt;E. Cost&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has always been a large difference between Eastern Europe and India. A decade ago, senior engineers could be hired for around a thousand per month in India. Today, 20% pay increases every six months translate into an annual 45% wage escalation. Only new engineers are cheaper than Poland’s, proving that India will become more expensive as a whole within two to three years. Although the US dollar has suffered the last couple of years, the Polish zloty has not escalated like the Indian rupee. Therefore, Neubloc has actually decreased prices due to the expansion of our customer relationships, instead of increasing the price of developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;To learn more about the benefits of outsourcing to Poland, please contact:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armando Viteri, President&lt;br&gt;
Email: &lt;span id=&quot;cloak19893&quot;&gt;This email address is being protected from spambots. You need JavaScript enabled to view it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;script type='text/javascript'&gt;
 //&lt;!--
 document.getElementById('cloak19893').innerHTML = '';
 var prefix = '&amp;#109;a' + 'i&amp;#108;' + '&amp;#116;o';
 var path = 'hr' + 'ef' + '=';
 var addy19893 = '&amp;#97;v&amp;#105;t&amp;#101;r&amp;#105;' + '&amp;#64;';
 addy19893 = addy19893 + 'n&amp;#101;&amp;#117;bl&amp;#111;c' + '&amp;#46;' + 'c&amp;#111;m';
 var addy_text19893 = '&amp;#97;v&amp;#105;t&amp;#101;r&amp;#105;' + '&amp;#64;' + 'n&amp;#101;&amp;#117;bl&amp;#111;c' + '&amp;#46;' + 'c&amp;#111;m';
 document.getElementById('cloak19893').innerHTML += '&lt;a ' + path + '\'' + prefix + ':' + addy19893 + '\'&gt;'+addy_text19893+'&lt;\/a&gt;';
 //--&gt;
 &lt;/script&gt; &lt;br&gt;
Phone: (619) 322-6321&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">by Armando Viteri, Neubloc, CEO and President
With major backlash against outsourcing to India, many companies with investments there are now looking for alternatives. Although there is discussion on the wage structure, the issues of outsourcing development services in India are deeper. This paper explores the continual issues with outsourcing development services to India and the shift to other alternatives.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Advantages of Using Co-Design</title><link href="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-01-07-advantages-of-using-co-design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Advantages of Using Co-Design" /><published>2014-01-07T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2014-01-07T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/advantages-of-using-co-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://127.0.0.1:4000/mylinks/posts/2014-01-07-advantages-of-using-co-design/">&lt;p&gt;Designers usually are not the end-users of a given product, but most engineered products are marketed with little or no user input or involvement. Co-design is a design practice utilizing User Centered Design (UCD) that relies on user input to aid product design before marketing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has several advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;1. Greater customer demand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;2. Improved user adoption&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;3. Higher user satisfaction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;4. Increased product profitability
&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, co-designed products have many ROI benefits. By gathering user input early on in the design process, firms avoid costly fixes caused by mismanaged resources and time. Co-design seamlessly integrates with market-driven product management practices to identify market problems and how to solve them by interacting, observing and understanding the user’s needs. This brings target users into product planning and design, which increases the likelihood of success for the project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
For more information on co-design, see our full discussion &lt;a href=&quot;../case-studies/white-papers/utilizing-co-design-to-create-market-driven-products.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/h4&gt;</content><author><name>Your Name</name></author><summary type="html">In today’s global and fast-paced economy, outsourcing provides enriching opportunities for companies that save both time and money. However, in order to make the most of these third parties, it is important to understand their advantages as well as their disadvantages.</summary></entry></feed>
